# ROBERT WILLIFORD

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Software Engineer

Vacc

m 09/2020 - Ongoing

**♀** Raleigh, NC

**Technical Recruiting and Consulting** 

 Freelance, full-stack software development consulting on various client projects. Industries include freight supply chain and entertainment industries. Majority of projects utilize AWS, OpenJDK 11, and/or React/NodeJS.

# Software Engineer

PrecisionHawk

**11/2019 - 09/2020** 

**♀** Raleigh, NC

Drone/Software Solutions for Energy and Agriculture

• Full-stack react and java8/openjdk development on AWS infrastructure for an application that allows energy companies to monitor the transmission lines and components of their electrical grid infrastructure.

# Software Engineer

IRM

**10/2019 10/2019** 

**♀** RTP

Cloud, IT, and IoT solutions

 Built automated solutions using Python for database data migrations for quote to cash financial information. Worked on distributed cloud-native application with a distributed systems back-end implemented in Go and using Kubernetes. Focusing on optimizing data-streaming capabilities for file upload/download, and gathering and aggregating associated financial metadata. (CIO department).

# Software Engineer

Cisco

**1** 06/2017 - 03/2019

**₽** RTP

Digital Security and Networking Solutions

 Full-stack web development. (Web application that assesses the viability of software images to be deployed to production systems by analyzing file contents). Led the development on service integrations and page navigation mechanisms, and expanded the functionality of numerous back-end services. Deployed on a hybrid-cloud infrastructure.

# **Back-End Developer**

iCiDigital

**1** 02/2017 - 06/2017

**♀** Raleigh, NC

Software Consultancy

# Junior Web Developer

The Iron Yard

**#** 09/2016 - 12/2016

**♀** Durham, NC

Web Development Bootcamp

# Data Analyst

Stealz, Inc.

**1** 05/2016 - 08/2016

Raleigh, NC

Mobile Internet Marketing Application

# Graduate Research Assistant

North Carolina State University

**1** 05/2015 - 08/2015

Raleigh, NC

Machine Learning Lab

#### **EDUCATION**

# B.S. Environmental Science/Mathematics

North Carolina State University

**1** 08/2011 - 05/2016

Raleigh, NC

# **SUMMARY**

I like pushing the boundaries of what people think is possible, and working on applications that have the potential to shift paradigms. I value and like to help cultivate empathy and collaboration in a team oriented environment. (4+ years of startup and enterprise experience)

#### **SKILLS**

# Languages

Ruby Javascript

Java

Python

Go

#### Frameworks

Ruby on Rails

NodeJS

Buffalo

ReactJS

Flask

Spring

# Infrastructure

PostgreSQL R

**Apache Sling** 

Redis

Heroku

MariaDB

Git

lira

Linux

Kubernetes

CassandraDB IBMCloud

CloudFoundry

nginx

AWS

ElasticSearch

# Libraries and Templating

Bootstrap

jQuery

Sidekiq

ERB

CarbonUl

# **PASSIONS**

<

Open Source

Physics/Mathematics

7

**Environment** 

×

Traveling